When was the last time you owned your values
and those values were the reason for a great day at work
or a draining one?
Your first move is to get crystal clear
on your own leadership blueprint.
We call this your M.V.P. plus V,
your mission, vision, purpose, and values.
This is what we call your foundation for forever,
for your entire life.
And it directly informs how you lead.
Let's quickly define the terms so you can have clarity
as you go through your playbook drill.
Your purpose is your fundamental why.
It's the lasting impact you want to have.
Your vision is your where.
It's the vivid picture of the future
and what you're creating,
both personally and professionally.
And your mission is your how.
It's what you do every day to make that vision a reality.
When you lead from this place of clarity,
your coaching is an act of alignment.
When you're disconnected from it,
you risk misalignment, which can lead to burnout.
That internal conflict between what you value
and what you do is massively energy draining.
I once coached an executive who was brilliant,
but miserable.
After this exercise,
she realized a core value was creativity,
yet her role had become purely administrative.
Her work was misaligned with her purpose.
Armed with this clarity,
she proposed carving out time for an innovation task force.
Her leader agreed,
and her energy and performance skyrocketed
because her work was now fueling her.
Now, head to your playbook for drill 2.2.
Your play is to complete the M.V.P. audit
to define your own mission, vision, and purpose.
Then identify one low value task you can delegate
or diminish this week to better align your M.V.P.
and reclaim your energy.
Once you've completed that drill,
join me in the next video,
where we'll shift focus from leading self
to leading others by creating a climate
of psychological safety.